Guide to the Lowell Fitz Randolph papers, 1936-1979.
Randolph, Lowell Fitz papers, 1936-1979.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lowell Fitz Randolph papers, 1936-1979.
21-17-1876
Lowell Fitz Randolph, 1894-1980.
4 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, correspondence, reports, publications, notes, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, correspondence, reports, publications, notes, and other papers concerning corn and iris breeding.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lowell Fritz Randolph (Cornell University Ph.D. 1921) was professor of botany at Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, correspondence, reports, publications, notes, photographs, slides, field notes, and other papers concerning corn, iris breeding and his trips to Mexico, Honduras, Guatemala, the West Indies, Europe, India, Soviet Union (USSR) and the Middle East.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Randolph, Lowell Fitz, 1894-1980.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Corn--Breeding.; Iris (Plant); Botany.; Botanists.; College teachers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Slides (Photography); Field notes
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Iris Records
Subseries Ia. Field Trip Notebooks
Series II. Manuscript material
Series III. Subject Files
Series IV. Slides
Series V. Items
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Iris records
  - Envelopes containing photos of Iris (Box 4, Folder 1-10)
  - Society for Louisiana Irises - Newsletters, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fa Iris - Correspondence, 1950s-1960s (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fa Iris - Cytology - Original Photos/drawings (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fa Iris - Basic Data Analysis, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - P.C. M., 1970s (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Osler and Wilkes, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Ernest Sprague, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Maps (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Mexico - Data Sheets, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Tripsacum Manuscript, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Mexico - Data Sheets (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Mexico - Maps (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Awards, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Field Notes (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Glossary Excerpts - Definitions (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Field Trip - Listing of Collections, Memos on Tripsacum, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Field Trips - Mexico, Honduras and Diaries, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - West Indies Tripsacum - Travel plans, maps, herb. records (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Diagnostic Features of Herb. Specs., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Tripsacum Records (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - West Indies - Travel, Herb. Specs., 1971 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - West Indies - Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - West Indies - Tripsacum - M.S., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - N.Y. Botanical Garden (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Publications by Randolph (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Iris Species and Herbarium Species Notes: India and the USSR, 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    handwritten notes and Correspondence
  - Iris Species Correspondence and Sketch, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Iris Species Letter and Photographs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    British Museum
  - Iris Species Photographs, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    Photographs and negatives
  - Field Notes, Iris Trips and Iris Crossing Notes - Bundled, 1947-1969 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Bundles of loose handwritten notes. Includes notes from Boston(1949), England(1950 and 1959), St. Louis(1952), Indiana(1953), Lousiana(1964), Mexico, Honduras, and Guatemala(1965-1969) and Iris Crossing notes from 1947, 1948, 1949 and 1950
  - Field Trip Notebooks
    - Iris Trip Notebook - Europe(England) and Philadelphia, 1936-1939 (Box 6, Volume 1)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes
    - Iris Trip Notebook - Auto Trips, 1937-1953 (Box 6, Volume 2)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes. Includes trips to Florida, Washington, Adirondacks, Boston, and Nashville,
    - Field Notes - Southwest and Mexico Trip, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Volume 3)
    - Field Notes - Guatemala, 1946 (Box 6, Volume 4)
    - Iris Trip Notebook, 1949 (Box 6, Volume 5)
    - Field Notes - Europe, 1950 (Box 6, Volume 6)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes. Includes England, France, Denmark, and Sweden
    - Iris Trip Notebook - Europe and Middle East, 1954 (Box 6, Volume 7-8)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes. Includes Switzerland, France. Italy, Yugoslavia, Germany, Austria, Cypress, Turkey, Lebanon, and Egypt
    - Field Notes - California, Louisiana, Southwest, and Texas, 1956 (Box 6, Volume 9)
    - Field Notes - Memphis, Tennessee, 1957 (Box 6, Volume 10)
      6x9" notebook of handwritten notes
    - Iris Trip Notebook - India and Soviet Union(USSR), 1958-1959 (Box 6, Volume 11-12)
    - Iris Trip Notebook - "Iron Curtain Countries", 1961 (Box 6, Volume 13)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes. Includes N. Italy, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Poland and West Germany, Canary Islands and Sinica(China)
    - Field Notes - Mexico, Honduras and Guatamala, 1966 (Box 6, Volume 14)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes.
    - Field Notes - Mexico, 1971 (Box 6, Volume 15)
    - Field Notes - West Indies, 1971 (Box 6, Volume 16)
    - Field Notes - Mexico, 1971-1978 (Box 6, Volume 17)
      Pocket sized notebook of handwritten notes. Mainly from 1971-1972, also includes loose notes with later dates
- Series II. Manuscripts material
  - Draft paper by Randolph - Contributions of Wild Relatives of Maize to the Evolbutionary History of Domisticated Maize (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report - Fairchild Tropical Garden, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Zea diploperennis notes (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Diagrams and photos used in book (Box 3)
- Series III. Subject files
  - Agricultural Origins (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Archeological digs (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Banerjee Thesis, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chromosones (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Climatic Changes, Condensation and Adaption (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Coix spatlic (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cytogenetics (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cytology (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Early Subsistence (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Euclaena (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fairchild Tropical Garden (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hybidization and Genetics (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Introgression of Corn (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Kato Manuscript - Text parts I and II (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Kato Manuscript - Text Parts II (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Kato Appendix 1A Tables 1-9 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Kato Appendix 1A Figures 1-79 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Kato Appendix 1B Tables 1-6 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Kato Appendix II Figures 1-39, Tables 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Kernal Row Numbers (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Kyoto University - Scientific expedition to Latin American report (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Maize Genetics Cooperation Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Maydac (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Morphology (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Oaxaca Valley (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Origins of Corn (Box 1, Folder 28-20)
  - Origins of Corn (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Personal correspondence (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Peruvian Archeology (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Plant Genera (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Pollen (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Quotes (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Races of Corn (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rado Carbon Dating (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Techuacan Archeological Botanical Project (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - Teosinthe and Maize (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Tobacco and Nicotiana (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tropacum and Maize (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Wheat and Barley (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Zea Mays-Phylogeny (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Series IV. Slides
  - Concerning Tripsacum and various trips to Guatemala, Mexico, Adirondacks, etc. (Box 5)
- Series V. Items
  - Shells, with classification, MU-385, MU 462-477 (Box 7)